{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Convert the following SOP expression to an equivalent POS expression.", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Determine the values of A, B, C, and D that make the sum term  equal to zero.", "opta": "A = 1, B = 0, C = 0, D = 0", "optb": "A = 1, B = 0, C = 1, D = 0", "optc": "A = 0, B = 1, C = 0, D = 0", "optd": "A = 1, B = 0, C = 1, D = 1", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following expressions is in the sum-of-products (SOP) form?", "opta": "(A + B)(C + D)", "optb": "(A)B(CD)", "optc": "AB(CD)", "optd": "AB + CD", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Derive the Boolean expression for the logic circuit shown below:", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "From the truth table below, determine the standard SOP expression.", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One of De Morgan's theorems states that . Simply stated, this means that logically there is no difference between:", "opta": "a NOR and an AND gate with inverted inputs", "optb": "a NAND and an OR gate with inverted inputs", "optc": "an AND and a NOR gate with inverted inputs", "optd": "a NOR and a NAND gate with inverted inputs", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The commutative law of Boolean addition states that A + B = A \u00d7 B.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Applying DeMorgan's theorem to the expression , we get ________.", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The systematic reduction of logic circuits is accomplished by:", "opta": "using Boolean algebra", "optb": "symbolic reduction", "optc": "TTL logic", "optd": "using a truth table", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which output expression might indicate a product-of-sums circuit construction?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An AND gate with schematic \"bubbles\" on its inputs performs the same function as a(n)________ gate.", "opta": "NOT", "optb": "OR", "optc": "NOR", "optd": "NAND", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the SOP expression , how many 1s are in the truth table's output column?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "5", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A truth table for the SOP expression  has how many input combinations?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "4", "optd": "8", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many gates would be required to implement the following Boolean expression before simplification? XY + X(X + Z) + Y(X + Z)", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "4", "optd": "5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Determine the values of A, B, C, and D that make the product term  equal to 1.", "opta": "A = 0, B = 1, C = 0, D = 1", "optb": "A = 0, B = 0, C = 0, D = 1", "optc": "A = 1, B = 1, C = 1, D = 1", "optd": "A = 0, B = 0, C = 1, D = 0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the primary motivation for using Boolean algebra to simplify logic expressions?", "opta": "It may make it easier to understand the overall function of the circuit.", "optb": "It may reduce the number of gates.", "optc": "It may reduce the number of inputs required.", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many gates would be required to implement the following Boolean expression after simplification? XY + X(X + Z) + Y(X + Z)", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "4", "optd": "5", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "AC + ABC = AC", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When  are the inputs to a NAND gate, according to De Morgan's theorem, the output expression could be:", "opta": "X = A + B", "optb": "", "optc": "X = (A)(B)", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which Boolean algebra property allows us to group operands in an expression in any order without affecting the results of the operation [for example, A + B = B + A]?", "opta": "associative", "optb": "commutative", "optc": "Boolean", "optd": "distributive", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Applying DeMorgan's theorem to the expression , we get ________", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When grouping cells within a K-map, the cells must be combined in groups of ________.", "opta": "2s", "optb": "1, 2, 4, 8, etc.", "optc": "4s", "optd": "3s", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Use Boolean algebra to find the most simplified SOP expression for F = ABD + CD + ACD + ABC + ABCD.", "opta": "F = ABD + ABC + CD", "optb": "F = CD + AD", "optc": "F = BC + AB", "optd": "F = AC + AD", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Occasionally, a particular logic expression will be of no consequence in the operation of a circuit, such as a BCD-to-decimal converter. These result in ________terms in the K-map and can be treated as either ________ or ________, in order to ________ the resulting term.", "opta": "don't care, 1s, 0s, simplify", "optb": "spurious, ANDs, ORs, eliminate", "optc": "duplicate, 1s, 0s, verify", "optd": "spurious, 1s, 0s, simplify", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The NAND or NOR gates are referred to as \"universal\" gates because either:", "opta": "can be found in almost all digital circuits", "optb": "can be used to build all the other types of gates", "optc": "are used in all countries of the world", "optd": "were the first gates to be integrated", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The truth table for the SOP expression  has how many input combinations?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "4", "optd": "8", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Converting the Boolean expression LM + M(NO + PQ) to SOP form, we get ________.", "opta": "LM + MNOPQ", "optb": "L + MNO + MPQ", "optc": "LM + M + NO + MPQ", "optd": "LM + MNO + MPQ", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A Karnaugh map is a systematic way of reducing which type of expression?", "opta": "product-of-sums", "optb": "exclusive NOR", "optc": "sum-of-products", "optd": "those with overbars", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Boolean expression  is logically equivalent to what single gate?", "opta": "NAND", "optb": "NOR", "optc": "AND", "optd": "OR", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Applying the distributive law to the expression , we get ________.", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mapping the SOP expression , we get ________.", "opta": "(A)", "optb": "(B)", "optc": "(C)", "optd": "(D)", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Derive the Boolean expression for the logic circuit shown below:", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is the correct logic function for this PAL diagram?", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the SOP expression , how many 0s are in the truth table's output column?", "opta": "zero", "optb": "1", "optc": "4", "optd": "5", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mapping the standard SOP expression , we get", "opta": "(A)", "optb": "(B)", "optc": "(C)", "optd": "(D)", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which statement below best describes a Karnaugh map?", "opta": "A Karnaugh map can be used to replace Boolean rules.", "optb": "The Karnaugh map eliminates the need for using NAND and NOR gates.", "optc": "Variable complements can be eliminated by using Karnaugh maps.", "optd": "Karnaugh maps provide a cookbook approach to simplifying Boolean expressions.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Applying DeMorgan's theorem to the expression , we get ________.", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the examples below expresses the distributive law of Boolean algebra?", "opta": "(A + B) + C = A + (B + C)", "optb": "A(B + C) = AB + AC", "optc": "A + (B + C) = AB + AC", "optd": "A(BC) = (AB) + C", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Applying DeMorgan's theorem to the expression , we get ________.", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an important feature of the sum-of-products (SOP) form of expression?", "opta": "All logic circuits are reduced to nothing more than simple AND and OR gates.", "optb": "The delay times are greatly reduced over other forms.", "optc": "No signal must pass through more than two gates, not including inverters.", "optd": "The maximum number of gates that any signal must pass through is reduced by a factor of two.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An OR gate with schematic \"bubbles\" on its inputs performs the same functions as a(n)________ gate.", "opta": "NOR", "optb": "OR", "optc": "NOT", "optd": "NAND", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the examples below expresses the commutative law of multiplication?", "opta": "A + B = B + A", "optb": "AB = B + A", "optc": "AB = BA", "optd": "AB = A \u00d7 B", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Determine the binary values of the variables for which the following standard POS expression is equal to 0.", "opta": "(0 + 1 + 0)(1 + 0 + 1)", "optb": "(1 + 1 + 1)(0 + 0 + 0)", "optc": "(0 + 0 + 0)(1 + 0 + 1)", "optd": "(1 + 1 + 0)(1 + 0 + 0)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The expression W(X + YZ) can be converted to SOP form by applying which law?", "opta": "associative law", "optb": "commutative law", "optc": "distributive law", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The commutative law of addition and multiplication indicates that:", "opta": "we can group variables in an AND or in an OR any way we want", "optb": "an expression can be expanded by multiplying term by term just the same as in ordinary algebra", "optc": "the way we OR or AND two variables is unimportant because the result is the same", "optd": "the factoring of Boolean expressions requires the multiplication of product terms that contain like variables", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following combinations cannot be combined into K-map groups?", "opta": "corners in the same row", "optb": "corners in the same column", "optc": "diagonal", "optd": "overlapping combinations", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}